icom.museum 2017-12-16

# ICOM Privacy Policy- ICOM

Last updated: 10 October 2015

This policy specifies how ICOM, as the entity responsible for processing, uses and protects the personal data that you communicate to it when you visit the website, become a member, submit an application, use the ‘ICOMMUNITY’ platform or take part in an event or activity organised by ICOM.   
This policy also deals with the use of cookies on our website.

ICOM is committed to protecting personal data and respecting privacy in accordance with Law no. 78-87 of 6 January 1978, Law no. 2004-801 of 6 August 2004, and European data protection regulations. 

ICOM has designated a Data Protection Officer (DPO) with the CNIL, the French authority for personal data protection.

ICOM suggests that you regularly check this page for updates to this policy. 

**HOW AND BY WHOM ARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?**

Your personal data may be collected by ICOM via the membership form, when you view and interact with pages on the website or the ICOMMUNITY, through the national and international committees to which you already belong, and when you send a membership request or submit an application.

Personal data are hosted within the European Union.

The ICOM website may host links to third party sites. If so, ICOM recommends that you read these third-party sites’ privacy policies carefully.

 **WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT?**

ICOM does not collect any data without your knowledge, and only collects data that are strictly necessary to achieving the purpose of the processing, namely aiding and improving the operation and use of the site, and enabling the organisation to operate in accordance with its purpose, as defined in its statutes. 

To this end, ICOM collects the following information:

-    When you visit the website and use the ‘ICOMMUNITY’: In general, the user can browse the ICOM site without revealing any personal information. The only information collected by ICOM during general browsing on the site is that sent to the server log (IP/Internet protocol, domain name, type of browser, operating system, the site you are connected from, the files you download, pages visited, dates and times of these visits, etc.) and any messages or comments that you post online.

-    When you request information via our contact form on the site:

-    When you contribute to ICOM’s website or activities (experts, authors, contributors, graphic designers, translators):

 **HOW DO WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED AND TO WHOM IS IT DISCLOSED?**

ICOM may pass on personal data to its partners for the purposes indicated below.   
ICOM does not pass on your personal data to third parties without your prior authorisation, unless current regulations require such data to be communicated, including upon request from the legal authority in accordance with legislative provisions. 

This information will be used by ICOM or its partners for the following purposes:

 **HOW LONG DO WE KEEP PERSONAL DATA?**

Information collected on the ICOM website is kept for a limited period until the purpose for which it was collected has been fulfilled, and provided you do not exercise your rights as detailed below. 

**SECURITY AND CONFIDENTIALITY OF PERSONAL DATA**

ICOM ensures the security of your information, to prevent its distortion, damage, or access by unauthorised third parties.

However, you are responsible for protecting the security of your account, your user name and password. 

If you believe that a third party knows or has changed your password, or that a third party can access the email address linked to your account, you are requested to inform ICOM without delay by writing to Mrs Brigitte Coutant, at the following email address: [brigitte.coutant@icom.museum](mailto:brigitte.coutant@icom.museum).

 **WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS?**

Provided you can prove your identity, you have at all times the right to access and to rectify your personal data.  
You also have the right to contest, for a legitimate reason, the processing of these data and their communication to third parties. 

ICOM can contest any requests that are clearly abusive, including but not exclusively in terms of their number, or their repetitive or systematic nature.   
These rights can be exercised by writing to Mrs Brigitte Coutant, at: [brigitte.coutant@icom.museum  
](mailto:brigitte.coutant@icom.museum)  
Users are informed that telephone requests will not be accepted. 

**WHAT ARE YOUR OBLIGATIONS?**

As a user of the [http://icom.museum](http://icom.museum/ "Opens internal link in current window") website, you must comply with the provisions of the amended Data Protection Law of 6 January 1978. Non-respect of this law is a penal offence. You must in particular, in respect of the personal data to which you have access, refrain from any collection or alternative use, and more generally any act, liable to violate the privacy and the basic rights and freedoms of individuals.

 **USE OF COOKIES AND SOCIAL MEDIA SHARING BUTTONS**

You are advised that when you view the website a cookie may be automatically installed on your device. The sole purpose of this cookie is to provide ICOM with anonymous information about your browsing on the site (analysis of visitor data, audience measurement) with the aim of improving the quality of the site. It cannot be used for individual identification.  
You can always configure your browser options so that you are advised when cookies are present and you may be able to refuse them. However, some features of the ICOM website cannot function properly without cookies activated.     
Social network sharing buttons are accessible on the site. We would like to draw your attention to the fact that these sharing buttons enable information about you to be collected. We suggest that you make yourself aware of the conditions of use of these data by reading the privacy policies of the social networks concerned, which are available on their websites.
